<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kgosi</title><link>https://modisek.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Kgosi</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;p>Copyright © 2021 Kgosietsile Modise&lt;/p></copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 11:25:52 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://modisek.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My workflow</title><link>https://modisek.github.io/posts/workflow/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 11:25:52 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://modisek.github.io/posts/workflow/</guid><description>
How to move fast in bash 1. Use an autojumper to move between directories An autojumper caches visited directories in its database and allows for direct jumping to known directories eliminating the need to type out the full path.I useone called zoxide, but they are may others worth trying out.
it has some sort of fuzzy pattern matching and allows me to type only part of the name of the directory zoxide demo</description></item><item><title>Move to Wayland</title><link>https://modisek.github.io/posts/move-to-wayland/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 12:53:12 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://modisek.github.io/posts/move-to-wayland/</guid><description>
In my previous linux setup blogpost i said i might switch to wayland from the aging Xorg, and the vulnerabilities that were found in Xorg weeks prior have fasttracked that switch and over the weeked i moved to sway.Sway being the most mature wayland compositor won me over, i had said that maybe will try hikari but have been desuaded by the lack of documentation. Sway is familliar to me since its a fork of i3, i have used i3 for a while in the past and the setup for both is simillar save for a few things which makes sense only on i3(xorg) i have had to find alternatives to my programs that depend on x, for example xclip, dmenu, sxhkd etc wont work on wayland but alternatives are available and work just as well</description></item><item><title>Playing With Openbsd</title><link>https://modisek.github.io/posts/playing-with-openbsd/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 00:25:03 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://modisek.github.io/posts/playing-with-openbsd/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="https://modisek.github.io/imgs/allen-ng.jpg"/>
Photo by Allen Ngon UnsplashWhat is openBSD Openbsd is a unix like operating system with a strong focus on security and also emphasizes standardization and corectness, correctness is ensured by extensive auditing of the source,making sure that there are no bugs to exploit.Their website says that openbsd has had &amp;ldquo;Only two remote holes in the default install, in a heck of a long time! &amp;ldquo;, this goes to show how secure it is.</description></item><item><title>terraform and ansible</title><link>https://modisek.github.io/posts/intro-to-terraform/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 18:23:11 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://modisek.github.io/posts/intro-to-terraform/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="https://modisek.github.io/imgs/website.jpg"/>
I wanted to use both ansible and terraform in a project for practice purposes and came up with a simple infrastructure to host my website in a ec2 instance using nginx.Terraform is used to provision infrastructure ie create an ec2 instance while ansible is used for configuration management ie installing all the software in the ec2 instance
prerequisites install the following using your distro package manager
terraform ansible set up aws credentials main use the aws provider provider &amp;quot;aws&amp;quot; { region = var.</description></item><item><title>Setting up linux using ansible</title><link>https://modisek.github.io/posts/ansible-dev-laptop/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 18:13:27 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://modisek.github.io/posts/ansible-dev-laptop/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="https://modisek.github.io/imgs/code.jpg"/>
image: https://unsplash.com/@ngeshlew
Automation is all the rage nowadays with concepts like infrastructure as code being very popular in all parts of computing, and since my setup hasnt changed much in years i decided it would benefit me to automate it so that the next time i need to reinstall i would not have to install and set up everything by hand.I had already hosted my dotfiles on git and used those in my previous installs, but this time i wanted to automate the installation of the applications as well not just their settings.</description></item><item><title>My Linux Dev Setup</title><link>https://modisek.github.io/posts/my-linux-dev-setup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 18:57:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://modisek.github.io/posts/my-linux-dev-setup/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="https://modisek.github.io/imgs/preview.png"/>
Why linux I have been using linux for a few years now and honestly i dont see myself going back to a non unix like operating system anytime soon,as a developer linux offers me powerful tools that help me be productive.The commandline is way more efficient and allows me to automate with ease some of my most common tasks.I have written a few bash scripts that help me with a few common daily things i do like watching youtube videos through mpv media player, a script to automate tmux so i can start working on a project faster.</description></item><item><title>My blog setup with hugo and github pages</title><link>https://modisek.github.io/posts/my-blog-setup/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 01:19:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://modisek.github.io/posts/my-blog-setup/</guid><description>
I wanted an easy and cheap way to create and host my blog site and hugo came out on top for its ease of setup, and i decided to host it on github pages since it was free.You can find out more about github pages and hugo ,hugo is a static site generator written in GO.
This are the steps i took to host my blog post
Create and host install hugo following instructions for your distro or operating system</description></item><item><title>Hello World</title><link>https://modisek.github.io/posts/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 13:51:11 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://modisek.github.io/posts/hello-world/</guid><description>
welcome to my blog!!
&amp;ldquo;You could be good today but instead you choose tomorrow&amp;rdquo; -marcus aurelias</description></item><item><title>Hello Friend</title><link>https://modisek.github.io/showcase/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 1986 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://modisek.github.io/showcase/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="https://modisek.github.io/imgs/hello.jpg"/>
"Hello, friend?" That's lame. Maybe I should give you a name?</description></item><item><title>Kgosietsile Modise</title><link>https://modisek.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://modisek.github.io/about/</guid><description>
Hi there 👋 I am kgosietsile modise a fullstack developer from botswana I am fullstack developer from botswana with an interest in cloud/devops, I know Html5, Css3 and Javascript, React and Gatsby js, but am platform and language agnostic and have used Java spring boot for my backend, python and also android development using java seedling I’m currently learning React and other frameworks that use React, terraform, ansible, aws
linkedin github</description></item><item><title>Uses</title><link>https://modisek.github.io/uses/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://modisek.github.io/uses/</guid><description>
Editor vim/neovim custom theme terminus font Terminal bash custom colors Setup(PC) Os void linux(musl) swaywm foot terminal emulator wrote about my setup
Specs potato</description></item></channel></rss>